Guide to the Ted Fagan Collection
Stanford Archive of Recorded Sound
Ted Fagan Collection
1920-1990
ARS-0008
Fagan, Ted
72 linear ft.
Stanford Archive of Recorded Sound Stanford University Libraries Stanford, California 94305-3076
Fagan's collection consists primarily of reel to reel tapes (1033). The rest of the materials are music memorabilia, Fagan's own writings and documents concerning the United Nations.
Access
Collection is open for research. Listening appointments may require 24 hours notice. Contact the Archive Operations Manager.
Biography / Administrative History
Theodore Fagan, of Jewish-English background was born in Buenos Aires, Argentina on Feb. 21, 1921. His early education included five years at a boarding school in England. Back in Argentina he completed a degree in Civil Engineering (1943). Two years later he came to New York, and within months was hired as a United Nations Spanish, French and English interpreter. One of his earlier assignments included the Nuremberg War Trials (1946), and through his thirty-year long involvement with the UN he interpreted speeches from leaders such as Prime Minister Fidel Castro and President L?opold S. Senghor of Senegal. Fagan was an indefatigable writer, his many writings include two historical novels --on Evita Per?n, and on the famous 19th century Parisian lawsuit of La Ronci?re-- a historical drama, Elizabeth Rex, produced in Los Angeles (1963), and his memoirs on his long association with the United Nations. Fagan had a life-long passion for music and collected music memorabilia and recordings. After retiring form his work at the UN, at age 55, he collaborated with William R. Moran on The encyclopedic discography of Victor recordings. Matrix series 1 through 4999: the Victor Talking Machine Company, 24 April 1903 to 7 January 1908, published by Greenwood Press in 1986. Fagan died in New York in 1987.
Scope and Content of Collection
Throughout his life and multiple travels associated with his UN work, Ted Fagan collected music memorabilia, and over a thousand reel to reel recordings, which are primarily operatic. Fagan recorded several compilations of selected opera singers, often organized by voice range. Among the reel to reels are the annual UN Human Rights Day concerts and some intriguing tapes such as the contested recordings of Richard Wagner conducting a passage of Act II of Tristan und Isolde, presumably from 1880, and possibly of soprano Jenny Lind singing Ah! non giunge, from Bellini?s Sonnambula, from 1883. Among the music memorabilia are two Medieval manuscripts, a notated missal leaf with musical notation, from about the late 10th and early 11th century and a leaf from the church canon from the 12th or 13th century; a British engraved vocal piece from the 18th century; a letter by Gaspare Spontini from 1847 and a program autographed by Aaron Copland. Among the art works are two engravings depicting Fryderyk Chopin and Marie Falcon, a lithograph of Jenny Lind, and about a dozen etchings by the Spanish artist Vicente Gand?a. The collection also includes over fifty photographs, most of which are autographed, Fagan?s multiple writings, and a large body of documents relating to the United Nations and interpreting.
Arrangement
Series Description: 1. Photographs; 2. Art work; 3. Music memorabilia; 4. Programs; 5. Opera notes; 6. Reel to reel tapes; 7. Discs; 8. Cassettes; 9. Video tapes' 10. Fagan's writings.
Indexing Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the library's online public access catalog.
Fagan, Ted; Operas--Excerpts
Container List
- Photographs
  - Autographed
    - Addison, Adele (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Albanese, Licia (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Alsen, Elsa, 1880-1975 (2 photographs) (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Bernstein, Leonard, 1918-1990 (2 photographs) (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Björling, Jussi, 1911-1960. 1958 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Borkh, Inge (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Branzell, Karin, 1891-1974. 1958 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Cavalieri, Lina, 1874-1944 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Damrosch, Frank, 1859-1937 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Damrosch, Walter, 1862-1950 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Elman, Mischa, 1891-1967. April, 1909 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Griller String QuartetDec. 14, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Pinza, Ezio (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Flagstad, Kirsten, 1895-1962 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Godowsky, Leopold, 1870-1938 Aug. 18, 1933 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Hammond, Joan, Dame, 1912- (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Henschel, George, Sir, 1850-1934 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Huberman, Bronislaw March 28, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Iturbi, Amparo, 1898-1969 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Kirsten, Dorothy, 1910-1992 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Kraus, Lili, 1903-1986 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Lawrence, Marjorie, 1921- (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Lehmann, Liza, 1862-1918 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Lehmann, Lotte (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Lewis, Brenda, 1921- (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Luboshutz, Pierre, 1891-1971 and Jenia (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - McCormack, John (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Merola, Gaetano (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Merrill, Robert (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Milanov, Zinka (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Muzio, Claudia, 1889-1936 1925 (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Paderewski, Ignace Jan, 1860-1941 (2 photographs) (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - Paganini String Quartet1946 (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - Palangi, Carl (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - Pettis, Grenville (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - Pons, Lily, 1898-1976 (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - Rethberg, Elisabeth, 1894-1976 (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - Rosé Quartet (Box 1, Folder 38)
    - Rosenthal, Moriz, 1862-1946 (Box 1, Folder 39)
    - Schumann-Heink, Ernestine, 1861-1936 (3 photographs) (Box 1, Folder 40)
    - Souzay, Ge'rard, 1918-2004 (Box 1, Folder 41)
    - Svanholm, Set. Aug. 19, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 42)
    - Szigeti, Joseph, 1892-1973 (Box 1, Folder 43)
    - Tebaldi, Renata (Box 1, Folder 44)
    - Thomas, John Charles, 1891-1960. (Box 1, Folder 45)
    - Turner, Eva, Dame, 1892-1990 (Box 1, Folder 46)
    - Waterman, Faith1933 (Box 1, Folder 47)
    - Weissenberg, Alexis (Sigi) (Box 1, Folder 48)
    - Belumy, H (Oversize 54, Folder 49)
      "Para mi excelente colaborador T. Fagin. H Belumy, 1959.
  - No Autograph
    - Two photographs of Callas, Maria, 1923-1977 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Fagin, Alfred Frank (Theodore's father)1921 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Fagan, Theodore1949/50 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Ferrier, Kathleen, 1912-1953 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Graham, Martha in a Letter to the World. Photograph by Morgan, Barbara (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Joachim, Joseph, 1831-1907 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Two photographs of Lehmann, Lotte (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Lehmann, Lotte (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Paderewski, Ignace Jan, 1860-1941 (4 photographs) (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Unidentified
    - Six unidentified photos (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Artwork
  - Gandon d' ápres Charpentier / Falcon, Marie-Cornélie, 1814-1897, Engraving (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Chopin, Frédéric, 1810-1849 / Lipinsky, Lino, Black and white photogrpah of painting (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Llanto del / Nourrit, Louis, Engraving (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Lind, Jenny, 1820-1887 / Sorony, N, Lithograph on stone (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - The Abbé / SpyMay 15, 1886, Lithograph (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Easy Execution / SpyDec. 28, 1899, Lithograph (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Italian Music / unknownFeb.15, 1879, Lithograph (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Music of the Future / SpyMay 19, 1877, Lithograph (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Patience / SpyMay 21,1881, Lithograph (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Gandía, Vicente. Acerca de Persephone, Etching. 11 x 9 in. (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Gandía, Vicente. Untitled. Vase with flowers (2), Etching 4 x 4 in.; pen drawing 6 x 5 in. (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Gandía, Vicente. Composición 2 (2), Etching13 x 10 in. b/w; Engraving13 x 10 in. color (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Gandía, Vicente. Composición 3. (Bowl with fruit), Etching 11 x 9 in. (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Gandía, Vicente. Media manzana, Etching 13 x 10 in. (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Gandía, Vicente. Granadas, Etching 11 x 10 in. (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Gandía, Vicente. Composición 3. (Flower pot), Etching 13 x 10 in. (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Gandía, Vicente. El Ausente, Etching 11 x 7 in. (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Gandía, Vicente. Cardinal en peligro, Etching 9 x 7 in. (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Gandía, Vicente. Untitled (2), Etching 3 x 3 in.; 7 x 6 in. (Box 2, Folder 19)
    Head and pigeon; Bowl with fruit
  - Gandía, Vicente. Desnudos, Etching 9 x 7 in. (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Gandía, Vicente. Las hermanas Mayor (2), Etching 9 x 6 in. (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Gandía, Vicente. Ilustración sobre un libro de Ted Fagan (2), Etching 10 x 7 in.; 12 x 8 in. (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Gandía, Vicente. El Poeta, Etching 10 x 8 in. (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Gandía, Vicente. Sketches of Ted Fagan (4), Carbon sketches 14 x 9 in. (Box 2, Folder 24)
    Three not signed, one signed
  - E. H. A Corner of Macaulay HouseJuly 23, Water color on sketching board 11 x 8 in. (Box 2, Folder 25)
    Filed with the water color is a postacard from Ockenden Manor, Cuckfield. Addressed to Ted Fagan singed by Andrew. Booklet Macaulay House, Fagan's boarding school
- Collectibles
  - Spontini, Gaspare, 1774-1851. Letter, Paris May 6, 1847 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    Recommending to his "dear colleague" the student Adolphe Donadieu. It would appear from the letters content that the intended addressee is Auber, D. F. E. (Daniel François Esprit), 1782-1871.
  - Autographs by: Bauer, Harold, 1873-1951; Godowsky, Leopold, 1870-1938; Hardelot, Guy d', 1858-1936; McCormack, John, 1884-1945; Weingartner, Felix, 1863-1942; three unidentified (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Copland, Aaron, 1900-1990. Autographed program1968 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Two autographed programsAug. 23, 1954; Feb.29, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    Playhouse in the park; Vishnevskaya, Galina, 1926- vocal recital
  - Four autographed Metropolitan Opera Announcements (Box 2, Folder 5)
    Spanning from 1913-1929
  - Cover for a duet for Jenny Lind and Marietta Alboni (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Morpurgo, Adolfo. Suite for viola da gamba soloOct. 1956 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    Music manuscript with dedication, "Para mi distinguido amigo y gran cultor [?] del arte, Ted Fagan muy afectuosamente. Adolfo Morpurgo"
  - Printed songs from the Illustrated London News1854-57 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    Bishop, Henry R. The king and the miller of Dee; Mid' the new-mown hay; The eolian harp -- Mori, Frank, 1820-1873. Thank you God for Peace; The Russian national anthem; The trusting heart; O leave her to her grief; Farewell to the Woodlands -- Gray, John. The Baltic fleet -- March composed by her excellency the wife of Omer Pacha
  - Engraved music and color illustration entitled, Ladies' lament for the loss of Senesino 1737 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Bettini Micro Phonograph poster (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Gandía, Vicente. Columbia Museum of Art. Art catalogueNov. 1968 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    Coloumbia, South Carolina. Autographed: "Saludos cordiales. Te abraza, Vicente." Enclosed are two b/w photographs of Vicente Gandía.
  - Leaf from a Medieval Full Missal, Vellum, 11" by 8 3/4"; sepia and red caligraphy (Oversize 54, Folder 12)
    Notated missal leaf. Liturgical text in Latin for the procession of the Feast of Purification of the Blessed Virgin Mary, followed by the Introit of the mass. With musical notation, neumes in campo aperto. Probably Old German-Lorraine neumes, but scarcely distinct from the St. Gall notation, dating from about the late 10th and early 11th century.
  - Leaf from a Church Canon, Vellum, 16" by 10"; 2 leaves, 4 pages; sepia, blue and red caligraphy (Oversize 54, Folder 13)
    Latin text in two columns with many abbreviations. Rubrication and initials marking paragraphs are standard and relatively simple. Some of the topics dealt with include, bishops residences, schimates or people who have stepped out of the church, usury and homicide. Probably dating from the 12th or 13th century.
  - Weill, Kurt, 1900-1950 title page manuscript (Oversize 54, Folder 11)
    Title page: " Zu Philipp Jarnach. Kurt Weil. Fantasia, Pasacaglia u. Hymnus. op.6."
  - Music manuscript, author unknown (Oversize 54, Folder 12)
    Two-page piano piece manuscript in pencil. Found together with the Kurt Weil title page (see 3.11). Top of first page "Ein bischen Liebe brauch man doch z. glückl. sein." Bottom second page "Nach Gesangabschluss noch 16 Takten Violin solo (mit Spring[?])" "folgt 9 a"
- Programs
  - Nine programs from 1950 to 1979 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Opera Notes
  - Fagan's opera book notes I (Box 3, Folder 1)
    Some of the main sections are: Gluck, Christoph Willibald, Ritter von, 1714-1787. Alceste (1776) -- Giordano, Umberto, 1867-1948. Andrea Chénier
  - Fagan's opera book notes II (Box 3, Folder 2)
    The main section deals with Bizet, Georges, 1838-1875. Carmen
  - Fagan's opera book notes III (Box 3, Folder 3)
    Some of the main sections deal with castrati and the legend of Faust in music
  - Fagan's opera book notes IV (Box 3, Folder 4)
    The main sections deal with Monteverdi, Claudio, 1567-1643. Orfeo and to a lesser extent with Incoronazione di Poppea
  - Fagan's opera book notes V (Box 3, Folder 5)
    The main sections deal with singing in general and Puccini, Giacomo, 1858-1924. Tosca
  - Fagan's opera book notes VI (Box 3, Folder 6)
    The main section deals with the opening of the San Francisco Opera
  - Miscellaneous (Box 3, Folder 7)
    List of singers in Le Theatre 1898-1913; In Memoriam Kathleen Ferrier
- Reel to reel tapes
  - Mahler, Gustav, 1860-1911. Kindertotenlieder (Tape missing) Feb. 20, 1960, 7" reel (Folder 225)
    New York Philharmonic Orchestra. Bernstein, Leonard, 1918-1990, conductor
  - Voices from the Past. BBC (Tape missing), 7" reel (Folder 226)
  - (Folder 466)
    Tape and index card missing
  - 7" reel (Folder 468)
  - Ludwig, Christa, mezzo-soprano, 10" reel (Folder 643)
    (Fagan's original numbering I. Tape missing)
  - 10" reel (Folder 660)
    (Fagan's original numbering XVIII. Tape and card missing)
  - Songs in Spanish, 7" reel (Folder 1002)
    Memorias de mi vieja canción; El aguatero porteño; Adios novio; Canción de luna y cosecha; Camino del indio; No conozco el mar; Para ir a buscarte; Cita en la misma esquina; Sur; Monte virgen dónde está?; Y se enojó la paloma; Duerme
  - Handel, George Frideric, 1685-1759. Theodora, 7" reel (Folder 1004)
    (gaps in recording)
  - Verdi, Giuseppe, 1813-1901. Otello. Act II, 7" reel (Folder 1007)
  - Björling, Jussi, 1911-1960., 7" reel (Box 7, Folder 1)
    Stabat Mater. Cujus Animam -- Requiem. Ingemisco -- Offenbach, Jacques, 1819-1880. Belle Hélène. Jugement de Paris -- Tiggarstudent. Nu ar jar Pank -- Widestedt. Sjung din hela Langton. -- Dreams of long ago. Caruso, Enrico, 1873-1921, tenor -- Foster, Stephen, 1826-1864. Jeannie with the light brown hair. -- Sibelius, Jean, 1865-1957. op. 21, No.5 Lilacs -- Campbell-Tipton, Louis, 1877-1921. Spirit flower -- Wide. Nümmer du Sverige.
  - AGSA; AGSB, 7" reel (Box 7, Folder 2)
    (Taped from discs) Alda, Frances, singer. Puccini, Giacomo, 1858-1924. Trittico. Gianni Schicchi. O mio babbino caro; Bohème. Donde lieta uscì -- Dalmorès, Charles, 1871-1939, singer. Meyerbeer, Giacomo, 1791-1864. Prophète. Roi du ciel et des anges -- Saint-Saëns, Camille, 1835-1921. Samson et Dalila. Arrêtez, Ô mes frères -- Farrar, Geraldine, 1882-1967 and Clément, Edmond, 1867-1928, singers. Schumann, Robert, 1810-1856. Duets, voices, piano, op. 34. Unterm Fenster -- Godard, Benjamin, 1849-1895. Dante. Nous allons partir tous les deux
  - AGSA; AGSB, 7" reel (Box 7, Folder 3)
    (Taped from discs) Kurz, Selma, 1874-1933, singer. Tosti, Paolo, Sir, 1846-1916. Ave Maria -- Massenet, Jules, 1842-1912. Manon. Obéissons quand leur voix appelle -- Ruffo, Titta, 1877-1953, singer. Thomas, Ambroise, 1811-1896. Hamlet. Spectre infernal -- Malena. Ma tu sfiorata; Disse il saggio -- Caruso, Enrico, 1873-1921, singer. Costa. Sei morta nella vita mia -- Posadas. Noche feliz -- Alda, Frances, singer. Puccini, Giacomo, 1858-1924. Manon Lescaut. In quelle trine morbide; Manon Lescaut. Ora, o Tirsi, è vaga e bella -- Cenna delle Beffe. Michiamo Lisabetta; Sempre cosi
  - Onégin, Sigrid, 1889-1943, 7" reel (Box 7, Folder 4)
    (Taped from discs) Meyerbeer, Giacomo, 1791-1864. Huguenots. Dame noble et sage -- Meyerbeer, Giacomo, 1791-1864. Prophète. O prêtres de Baal -- Verdi, Giuseppe, 1813-1901. Trovatore. Condotta ell'era in ceppi -- Verdi, Giuseppe, 1813-1901. Ballo in maschera. Re dell'abisso affrettati -- Bizet, Georges, 1838-1875. Carmen. Habanera; Carmen. Mêlons! coupons! -- Rubinstein, Anton, 1829-1894. Neue Liebe -- Lotti, Antonio, d. 1740. Pur dicesti, o bocca bella -- Bizet, Georges, 1838-1875. Pastorale -- Weckerlin, J.-B. (Jean-Baptiste), 1821-1910. Jeune fillette
  - De Luca, Giuseppe, 1876-1950, 7" reel (Box 7, Folder 5)
    (Taped from discs) Meyerbeer, Giacomo, 1791-1864. Pardon de Ploërmel. Ah! mon remords te venge -- Diaz, Eugène, 1837-1901. Benvenuto Cellini. De l'art splendeur immortelle -- Verdi, Giuseppe, 1813-1901. Don Carlos. C'est mon jour; Trovatore. Balen del suo sorriso -- Rigoletto. Pari siamo!; Traviata. Di Provenza il mar
  - Landowska, Wanda, 7" reel (Box 7, Folder 6)
    Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus, 1756-1791. Fantasia, piano K. 385g (397), D minor; Landowska speaks on playing Mozart; Sonata K. 311 in D major; Rondo K.11 in A minor
  - Boito, Arrigo, 1842-1918. Mefistofele, 7" reel (Box 7, Folder 7)
    Prologue; Acts 1, 2, 3; Epilogue. Teatro dell'opera (Rome, Italy) Orchestra and Chorus. Christoff, Boris, bass; Prandelli, Giacinto, 1914-, tenor; Moscucci, Clara (sic Orietta, soprano ?)
  - Miscellaneous Instrumental Music, 7" reel (Box 7, Folder 8)
    (Taped from discs) Track 1. Orchestre de la Suisse romande. Ansermet, Ernest, 1883-1969, conductor. Halaerts, bassoon. Vivaldi, Antonio, 1678-1741. Concerto in D minor for bassoon, harpsichord and strings. -- Orchestra de la Suisse romande. Ansermet, Ernest, 1883-1969, conductor. Revesky, R, oboe. Marcello, Benedetto, 1686-1739. Concerto in C minor for oboe and strings -- Gomberg, Ralph, oboe. Handel, George Frideric, 1685-1759. Sonata, oboe & continuo. -- Szigetti, Joseph, 1892, violin; McGinnis, clarinet; Miller, oboe; Gasman, english horn; Schoenbach, bass. Stravinsky, Igor, 1882-1971, conductor and composer. Pastorale, soprano, piano; arr.; Szigetti, Joseph, 1892, violin; Stravinsky, Igor, 1882-1971, piano. Mavra. Drug moî milyî -- Kell, Reginald, 1906-1981, clarinet. Philharmonia String Quartet. Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus, 1756-1791. Quintet, clarinet & string, K. 581, A major. -- Kell, Reginald, 1906-1981, clarinet. Moore, Gerald, 1924-, piano. Schumann, Robert, 1810-1856. Fantasiestücke, clarinet & piano, op. 73. No. 1. Track 2. Goodman, Benny, 1909-1986, clarinet; New York Philharmonic Orchestra. Barbirolli, John, Sir, 1899-1970, conductor. Debussy, Claude, 1862-1918. Rhapsody, clarinet & piano -- Brain, Aubrey, 1893-1955, horn. BBC Symphony Orchestra. Boult, Adrian, 1889-1983, conductor. Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus, 1756-1791. Concerto, horn, K. 417 E?major; Camden, Archie, 1888-1979, clarinet. Hallé Orchestra. Harty, conductor. Concerto, clarinet, K.191, B?major. -- Senaillé, Jean Baptiste, ca. 1688-1730. Sonatas, violin, continuo, 2e livre. No 5. Allegro spiritoso -- Kell, Reginald, 1906-1981, clarinet.London Symphony orchestra. Sargent, conductor. Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus, 1756-1791. Concerto, clarinet, K. 622, A major.
  - Through Childhood to a Throne. Her Majesty Queen Elizabeth II, 7" reel (Box 7, Folder 9)
    Speakers: Elizabeth II, Queen of Great Britain, 1926-; Duke of Edinburgh; Margaret, Princess of Great Britain, 1930-; George VI, King of Great Britain, 1895-1952; George V, King of Great Britain, 1865-1936; Attlee, C. R. (Clement Richard), 1883-1967; Churchill, Winston, 1871-1947; Eisenhower, Milton Stover, 1899-1985 -- Truman, Harry S., 1884-1972; Hitler, Adolf, 1889-1945; Roosevelt, Franklin D. (Franklin Delano), 1882-1945; Field Marshall Smutz; Evans, Emrys.; Neill, Wm. F. Sir
  - Duets, 7" reel (Box 7, Folder 10)
    (Taped from discs) Kirsten, Dorothy, 1910-1992, soprano; Merrill, Robert, 1917-2004, baritone. Bittersweet. I'll see you again -- Showboat. Why do I love you -- New moon. Wanting you -- When I grow to old to dream -- Fleische, singer; Bloch, singer. Strauss, Johann, 1804-1849. Zigeunerbaron. Wer uns getraut? -- Ljungberg, Göta, 1893-1955, soprano; Widdop, Walter, tenor. Wagner, Richard, 1813-1883. Parsifal. Ich sah' das Kind
  - Piano Concerti, 7" reel (Box 7, Folder 11)
    (Taped from discs) Uninsky, Alexander, 1910-1972, piano; Otterloo, Willem van, conductor. Chopin, Frédéric, 1810-1849. Concerto, piano, no. 1, op. 11, E minor -- Schnabel, Artur, 1882-1951, piano. London Symphony Orchestra. Sargent, Malcolm, Sir, 1895-1967, conductor. Beethoven, Ludwig van, 1770-1827. Concerto, piano, no. 1, op. 15, C major.
  - Schorr, Friedrich, 1888-1953, 7" reel (Box 7, Folder 12)
    (Taped from discs) Schumann, Robert, 1810-1856. Liederkreis, op. 39
  - Mysz-Gmeiner, Lula, 1876-1948, 7" reel (Box 7, Folder 13)
    Schubert, Franz, 1797-1828. Selections. Zwerg --Junge Nonne -- Seligkeit -- Forelle (Song) -- Tod und das Mädchen (Song) -- Sterne -- Nacht und Träume -- Litanei -- Echo -- Im Haine
  - Printemps, Yvonne, 1894-1977, 7" reel (Box 7, Folder 14)
    (Taped from discs) Messager, André, 1853-1929. Véronique. Selections -- Amour Masque. Selections -- Gerbault, Alain. Pot-pourri -- Offenbach, Jacques, 1819-1880. Grande duchesse de Gérolstein -- Lully, Jean Baptiste, 1632-1687. Air de Chloris -- Je sui avec toi. Mon rève s'aché -- Vertige d' un soir
  - Randolph, David. Music for the Connoisseur, 7" reel (Box 7, Folder 15)
    Drdla, Franz, 1868-1944. Souvenirs -- Sarasate, Pablo de, 1844-1908, composer and violin. Zigeunerweisen -- Tamagno, Francesco, 1850-1905, tenor. Verdi, Giuseppe, 1813-1901. Otello. Niun mi tema -- Saint-Saëns, Camille, 1835-1921. Suite algérienne. Marche militaire française -- Melba, Nellie, Dame, 1861-1931, soprano. Verdi, Giuseppe, 1813-1901. Otello. Piangea cantando -- Debussy, Claude, 1862-1918. Pelléas et Mélisande. Mes longs cheveux descendent -- Reszke, Edouard de, 1853-1917, singer. Verdi, Giuseppe, 1813-1901. Ernani. Infelice! e tu credevi -- London Baroque ensemble. Haas, Joseph, conductor. Haydn, Joseph, 1732-1809. Divertimento, 2 oboes, 2 horns & 2 bassoons, G major -- Joachim, Joseph, 1831-1907, violin. Brahms, Johannes, 1833-1897. Ungarische Tänze -- Lindsay. Congo -- Planquette, Robert, 1848-1903. Rip Van Winkle. Selections. (1900 cylinders, Joseph Jefferson) -- Grieg, Edvard, 1843-1907. Lyriske stykker, op. 43. Til foraret --
  - Gigli, Beniamino, 1890-1957, 7" reel (Box 7, Folder 16)
    Puccini, Giacomo, 1858-1924. Turandot. Nessun dorma -- Donizetti, Gaetano, 1797-1848. Elisir d'amore. Quanto è bella -- De Curtis, Ernesto, 1875-1937. Torna a Surriento -- Leoncavallo, Ruggiero, 1858-1919. Mattinata
  - Wagner, Richard, 1813-1883. Ring des Nibelungen. Götterdämmerung. Excerpts, 7" reel (Box 7, Folder 17)
    Flagstad, Kirsten, 1895-1962, soprano; Melchior, Lauritz, tenor. Metropolitan Opera (New York, N.Y.). Orchestra. Bodanzky, Artur, 1877-1939, conductor. Dawn duet, (May 12, 1939) -- Flagstad, Kirsten, 1895-1962, soprano. New York Philharmonic. Walter, Bruno, 1876-1962, conductor. Brünnhildes Schlussgesang, (May, 1952) -- Leider, Frida, 1888-1975, soprano; Thorborg, Kerstin, 1896-1970, alto; Janssen, Herbert, baritone; Melchior, Lauritz, tenor; List, Emanuel, bass. Royal Opera Orchestra of Covent Garden. Beecham, Thomas, Sir, 1879-1961, conductor. Höre mit Sinn. (May 14, 1936)
  - Melchior, Lauritz, tenor., 7" reel (Box 7, Folder 18)